<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better comments on DemoCamp</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Less is better comments</description>
    <item>
      <title>"DemoCamp": comment by Chris Nolan.ca</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John, nice to meet you tonight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2005 03:14:02 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2005/12/13/democamp#comment-56</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2005/12/13/democamp#comment-56</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"DemoCamp" by jlam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to &lt;a href="http://barcamp.org/index.cgi?SignUpHere"&gt;DemoCamp&lt;/a&gt; tonight and I saw a bunch of cool demos put on by folks working on startups here in Toronto.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.bubbleshare.com"&gt;BubbleShare&lt;/a&gt; folks had a really cool demo of an upcoming feature of their photo sharing service. They&amp;#8217;ve implemented the core interface of iPhoto using &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AJAX &lt;/span&gt;(you know the one: dragging a slider that dynamically resizes the thumbnails). You have to see it to believe it. Apparently this feature goes live on their site next week sometime.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re into ego surfing, you should definitely check out &lt;a href="http://ehlist.ca/"&gt;Eh List&lt;/a&gt;. Chris Nolan&amp;#8217;s done a really good job of aggregating a bunch of services to show you just where you rank (or don&amp;#8217;t) in the blogosphere.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;I&amp;#8217;m continually amazed by how Randy Charles Morin is able to generate revenue from his various ventures. Tonight he demonstrated &lt;a href="http://www.r-mail.org/"&gt;RMail&lt;/a&gt; which is a service that emails you &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds. Randy monetizes this by including links within the blog entries that point back to his custom search engine.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Sutha Kamal of &lt;a href="http://www.ambientvector.com"&gt;Ambient Vector&lt;/a&gt; demonstrated his social collaborative search engine that improves the quality of mobile search based on its analysis of your preferences and &lt;em&gt;your peer group&amp;#8217;s preferences&lt;/em&gt;. This is a really powerful idea that greatly improves the quality of recommendations, since you can think of search results as recommendations. This ties back into the idea that providing search context is a good thing.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It was also cool to hang out with &lt;a href="http://www.braithwaite-lee.com/weblog/"&gt;Reg Braithwaite&lt;/a&gt; again. Tonight I got a great idea about building a Firefox extension based on his ideas about context-based recommendations. I &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; want to do something cool in this space.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2005 00:31:00 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/12/13/democamp"&gt;DemoCamp&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
      <link>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/12/13/democamp"&gt;DemoCamp&lt;/a&gt;</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
