<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/stylesheets/rss.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better: A few quick notes</title>
    <link>http://iunknown.com/articles/2006/12/18/a-few-quick-notes</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>John Lam on software</description>
    <item>
      <title>A few quick notes</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost all of my attention has been focused on our upcoming move to Redmond. As I mentioned earlier, it&amp;#8217;s easily the most complicated thing that I&amp;#8217;ve had to organize in my life. We&amp;#8217;re in the end game now, and it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;feeling like it might actually happen!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m finishing up a consulting project at &lt;a href="http://www.husky.ca"&gt;Husky Injection Molding Systems&lt;/a&gt;. These guys create the machines that make a lot of the plastic goods that we consume &amp;#8211; ranging from pop bottles to laundry baskets. The guys that I work with are professional robot programmers &amp;#8211; and they&amp;#8217;re all over Microsoft&amp;#8217;s recent annoucement of the &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/robotics/"&gt;Microsoft Robotics Studio&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Industrial robots are optimized for performance, and aren&amp;#8217;t particularly intelligent &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s all about maximizing efficiency in the production of the goods. And while I didn&amp;#8217;t do any robotics programming myself, I&amp;#8217;m amazed by what they can accomplish given the lack of sophistication in the tools that they use to program these things. Some decent tools would go a long ways in improving the lives of robotics programmers &amp;#8211; and perhaps Robotics Studio is a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jamie Cansdale is organizing a charity auction to raise money for a safe drinking water and irrigation project in Malawi. There&amp;#8217;s lots of useful software that was graciously donated by various companies (and Jamie himself), so make sure you &lt;a href="net-developer-software-charity-auction.aspx"&gt;drop by his blog to take a look.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, I decided to give &lt;a href="http://ideas.live.com/programpage.aspx?versionId=4372c8c2-b76f-4d44-aea1-9835b61d8dc1&amp;nbsp;a"&gt;Windows Live Writer&lt;/a&gt; spin, and am using it to post this blog entry. I was amazed by how seamless the setup experience was for my &lt;a href="http://typosphere.org/"&gt;Typo-powered&lt;/a&gt; blog. I simply entered my blog&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;, and the username and password that I use to administer my blog. It auto-configured everything else. Color me impressed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2006 18:06:50 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:856b8d63-51a1-4dff-a964-8b38efc2a2cc</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://iunknown.com/articles/2006/12/18/a-few-quick-notes</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"A few quick notes" by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There will definitely be a bunch of work done on RubyCLR post my joining MSFT. It's just that the logistics of the move + my day job have more or less killed any free time that I had to work on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look for stuff happening in the new year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 11:08:19 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:fcb798bb-a5d1-4d28-94d5-c395700ff4db</guid>
      <link>http://iunknown.com/articles/2006/12/18/a-few-quick-notes#comment-1397</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"A few quick notes" by Justin</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glad to see you are still there Jon! Any chance RubyCLR is going to see love after you settle in at Microsoft?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, Merry Christmas! &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Dec 2006 14:10:47 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:5435987d-1dae-44ee-878e-d2443b6105ea</guid>
      <link>http://iunknown.com/articles/2006/12/18/a-few-quick-notes#comment-1393</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"A few quick notes" by Dan</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You haven't even moved to the states yet and you are already spelling like an American.  Colour me disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2006 22:47:16 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:74d338e4-008d-4966-96d3-7a0d826d34d5</guid>
      <link>http://iunknown.com/articles/2006/12/18/a-few-quick-notes#comment-1389</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
