<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better comments on A Life Changing Week</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Less is better comments</description>
    <item>
      <title>"A Life Changing Week" by jlam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year, I was fortunate enough to attend both &lt;a href="http://www.rubyconf.com"&gt;RubyConf&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.oopsla.org"&gt;OOPSLA&lt;/a&gt;. These conferences exposed me to many new ideas and lots of new people. If you&amp;#8217;re used to living in the Microsoft (or Java, or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;, or Linux, or Apple &amp;#8230;) world, it&amp;#8217;s a &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; good idea to break out of your monoculture and experience something different.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;For the Microsoft folks, instead of attending a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PDC&lt;/span&gt;, Tech Ed, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VS &lt;/span&gt;Live!, or DevConnections conference every year, choose to attend a different conference with your conference dollars. Attend a RubyConf or a &lt;a href="http://www.jaoo.org"&gt;JAOO&lt;/a&gt; or an &lt;a href="conferences.oreillynet.com/oscon/"&gt;OSCON&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.rubyonrails.com"&gt;Rails&lt;/a&gt; is hot this year, but something else will be hot next year.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;For me personally, I&amp;#8217;ve spent way too long in the statically typed languages world. Last year at the &lt;a href="http://www.eecg.toronto.edu/middleware2004/"&gt;Middleware&lt;/a&gt; conference in Toronto, &lt;a href="http://www.iona.com/blogs/vinoski/"&gt;Steve Vinoski&lt;/a&gt; and I had a great bonding moment when we recounted our recent experiences with &lt;a href="http://www.python.org"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;. At &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOPSLA&lt;/span&gt;, I had a chance to chat with some old-school &lt;a href="http://www.squeak.org"&gt;Smalltalk&lt;/a&gt; programmers (hello Jim!) who were more than happy to point out that most &amp;#8220;new&amp;#8221; language features in Python/Ruby were in existence long ago in Smalltalk. The same, of course, can be said for languages like C# as well :)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;That said, it&amp;#8217;s still important to use the right tool for the job. The libraries in the .NET world are simply too useful to be ignored. Bridging this gap is an itch I have to scratch. More on that soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2005 07:00:00 Eastern Daylight Time</pubDate>
      <guid>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/10/25/a-life-changing-week"&gt;A Life Changing Week&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
      <link>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/10/25/a-life-changing-week"&gt;A Life Changing Week&lt;/a&gt;</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
