<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/stylesheets/rss.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better: TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>John Lam on software</description>
    <item>
      <title>TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year is the 3rd year that I&amp;#8217;m a judge for the &lt;a href="http://www.sdmagazine.com/jolts/"&gt;Jolt Software Awards&lt;/a&gt;. A couple of nights ago, I thought that I had submitted my votes for the first round of voting to select the finalists. As it turns out, somewhere along the way my votes got lost (I blame my general sleep-deprived stupor these days).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Fortunately for me, I was running &lt;a href="http://www.timesnapper.com/"&gt;TimeSnapper&lt;/a&gt; at the time. This incredibly useful utility takes a snapshot of your desktop every 5 seconds and records the result as a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PNG&lt;/span&gt; image. So it was a simple matter to replay my day around the time I was entering my votes to see exactly what I voted for.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This morning I was chatting with my mother in law during our morning baby / toddler shift and I told her the story of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vannevar_Bush"&gt;Vannevar Bush&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; description of a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memex"&gt;Memex&lt;/a&gt; which was his vision of a life recorder. A modern implementation of Vannevar Bush&amp;#8217;s ideas is &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gordon_Bell"&gt;Gordon Bell&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://research.microsoft.com/barc/mediapresence/MyLifeBits.aspx"&gt;MyLifeBits&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;A fairly full day&amp;#8217;s worth of work for me is about 350MB worth of screenshots. That means that it would take about 100GB to store a year&amp;#8217;s worth of screenshots, which translates into about $40 Canadian dollars today. Now until this data is searchable, I doubt that it will be tremendously useful, but I find it fascinating that it costs so little to digitize an entire year&amp;#8217;s worth of my computer activity.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;If you could synchronize those screenshots with a keystroke logger and a network activity monitor, you could quickly make a quick-and-dirty searchable archive. Hmmmm &amp;#8230;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 10:10:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:2604debb9980976f8eed7fc76c4beaa2</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt</link>
      <category>Props</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by AtliB</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi John!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm happy to hear that TimeSnapper saved you time this way... although it's not it's primary function, it has actually helped me this way too! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next version that I and Leon are working on has an embedded database (FireBird) and we've already started logging some things like the .exe name of the active application and it's window caption and duration.   So the infrastructure for storing other things is getting into shape.  With this basic feature we can generate some really interesting statistics that could even help you work more efficiently!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to watch out for resource usage because we don't want to slow down the computer in any (noticable) way.  And also of course tackle most privacy issues :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it's feedback from people like you that sets the future direction for TimeSnapper so keep that coming!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!
Atli&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2006 14:04:20 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-314</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by Larry O'Brien</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;OneNote 12 applies OCR to searching across images. It's a very compelling feature. I think a key issue is that for search indexing, your OCR quality can be considerably below 100% and still be very, very useful. Also, as an indexing feature, it doesn't need to be realtime. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2006 13:48:01 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-313</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sorin,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to the size of each snapshot of the screen, we should be able to do more than just capture the captions of windows.  I agree that it would make it much easier to search, but what about capturing everything *in* the Window as well? For example, it would be fairly straightforward to simply save a copy of every HTML page that you viewed somewhere. We could also call GetWindowText() and friends to scrape content out of individual windows for non web apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'd be shocked if someone in academia wasn't already working on something like this (akin to the MyLifeBits project). It seems like such an obvious line of thinking in this space ...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2006 12:57:19 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-312</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by Sorin</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I'm sure Big Brother (read: some paranoid and micro management freaks at Big Corp) already took note and have plans to make the next user surveillance product.
How about logging active window captions to help with searching/indexing?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2006 12:09:11 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-311</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Larry,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work on multiple tasks each day - these days mostly non-billable work that I still need to account for (like the Jolts). I often forget what I was doing earlier in the day while filling out the timesheet, so this is a great way of jogging my memory. That plus the timeline feature lets me quickly scan to see what I was doing at different points in the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2006 08:27:04 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-310</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by Larry O'Brien</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Huh. Why, may I ask, do you choose to run such a utility? Did you expect to encounter such a need as you found? Do you have kids whose Internet behavior you want to monitor? &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 23:51:30 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-309</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by leon bambrick</title>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;network activity monitor (you just
    issued an HTTP POST to ...) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;good thinkin John. That's why we pay you the big bucks! (err... we don't actually pay anyone anything...)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just for the record too-- it wasn't me who left the 'null' comment above. But i like that guy's way of thinking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cheers
lb&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 17:47:56 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-308</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, no - I learned about it after the nomination phase was completed. Maybe next year ...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 08:14:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-307</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by null</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope timesnapper got your vote in the awards :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2006 03:39:59 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-306</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I've been spending some time thinking about and talking to some local folks here in Toronto about context and search. What's cool about recording the things that you're doing is that context is readily accessible. The more data you have, the better the computer can predict the context based on what you're doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the OCR idea, but I think the network activity monitor (you just issued an HTTP POST to ...) is also a very cool idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would be fun to work on something like this if I only had the time ...&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 20:55:11 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-305</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"TimeSnapper and Personal Life Recorders" by leon bambrick</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;it saved me too! but when i blogged about it, i got accussed of sounding like a 'marketing blog' (since i'm co-owner of timesnapper) ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;keystroke logger -- good -- but what about OCR? that's the direction i want to take timeSnapper. searchable yes -- and the trick of course is a ranking system, but not PageRank -- maybe AttentionRank -- we'll have to work on that once we have the data being stored, the types of indexing and ranking will be crucial. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;expect something clever though... we're doing our best! suggestions ideas welcome, and appreciated!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2006 18:47:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/18/timesnapper-saves-my-butt#comment-304</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
