<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better comments on Our other boy</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Less is better comments</description>
    <item>
      <title>"Our other boy": comment by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Odi - oh yes he does read. He's a bit impatient at this age so he sometimes skips one side of a page while reading, but he definitely reads all (well most) of the words out loud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more interesting books that he's reading now is a Weather Facts book that my wife used at school. The most impressive words that he can pronouce are "Synoptic Effects" :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now he doesn't really understand what a lot of the more esoteric words mean, but exposure helps his brain discover the relationship between words in different contexts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he definitely has a natural inclination towards books. He probably spends at least a couple of hours a day reading.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 16:04:50 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-106</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-106</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Our other boy": comment by Odi Kosmatos</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I'm impressed at your Boy's progress. I am certain this is no coincidence. I just &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; kids have this potential, and its up to the parents to bring it out and encourage it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you say "read", you really mean it, right? Not just look at pictures, but read the words, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2006 13:41:34 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-105</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-105</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Our other boy": comment by tomexou</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How a pretty, handsome, cute boy he is!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2006 03:35:23 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-88</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-88</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Our other boy": comment by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We're using a Logitech notebook mouse as well. The full-sized mice are just too large right now. We also remapped the right button to the left. Interestingly enough, he uses his thumb to click the mouse. I guess he's training himself for SMS text messaging already!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 10:21:18 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-82</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-82</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Our other boy": comment by Anson Tsao</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I find the Microsoft Wireless notebook mouse just about the right size for little hands, and using AutoHotKey to map right to left mouse button really helped.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 02:11:32 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-81</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy#comment-81</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Our other boy" by jlam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a long time since I&amp;#8217;ve posted about Matthew:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/23649168@N00/84578490/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/39/84578490_119d64f19d.jpg?v=0" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;He&amp;#8217;s almost 28 months old now, and he&amp;#8217;s starting his new pre-school on Wednesday. He&amp;#8217;s a pretty bright boy; he can read fairly elementary books completely on his own, and his vocabulary is growing by leaps and bounds. He was impressing his new pre-school teachers today by doing a &amp;#8220;reverse&amp;#8221; flash-card trick &amp;#8211; that is predicting the letter on the other side (these were the simple alphabet flashcards that have a picture on one side and a single letter on the other side) based on the picture. I guess all of Daddy&amp;#8217;s hard work creating his birthday present paid off! :)&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;We got Matthew his first computer for Christmas this year. Well, it was really just one of Daddy&amp;#8217;s older computers brought back to life with a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCI 802&lt;/span&gt;.11g wireless card. I was amazed by how quickly he learned how to use the mouse &amp;#8211; it took &lt;em&gt;maybe&lt;/em&gt; 2 days before he had it figured out. The hard part of course, is the fixed length of the cord, so you have to pick up the mouse or move it faster to get to where you want to go. We&amp;#8217;re not using a wireless mouse so that the mouse doesn&amp;#8217;t wander away.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;He figured out the Start button pretty quickly, so I had to lock down the options there (although he is running under a normal user account &amp;#8211; no admin privileges quite yet :). He also figured out how to start Explorer without any options present under the Start menu, and today he demonstrated his virtuosity with drop-down combo boxes &amp;#8211; I caught him browsing the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DVD&lt;/span&gt; drive today.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re working on typing skills next &amp;#8211; Textpad appears to be his editor of choice right now. I think it will take some time before his hands get big enough to start using emacs :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2006 18:57:00 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>&lt;a href="/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy"&gt;Our other boy&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
      <link>&lt;a href="/articles/2006/01/09/our-other-boy"&gt;Our other boy&lt;/a&gt;</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
