<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/stylesheets/rss.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>John Lam on software</description>
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft is like grad school</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m having a blast here at Microsoft. The last time I had this much fun was in grad school. The hallway and lunch conversations are excellent &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s great to be around so many smart folks. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just the other day I went to the equivalent of a departmental colloquium. One of the devs on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLR&lt;/span&gt; team gave an excellent description of how the debugging interfaces of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLR&lt;/span&gt; work. In all of my time outside of the company, I&amp;#8217;d never heard such a concise description of managed debugging, nor did I truly appreciate the challenges involved in implementing first class debugging support on the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLR&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s also &lt;strong&gt;vast&lt;/strong&gt; intranet. You can spend months just reading interesting papers. Now that I&amp;#8217;ve got &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RAS&lt;/span&gt; access to corpnet, I&amp;#8217;m spending some time each evening just reading. The opportunities for personal growth here are remarkable. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While I definitely underestimated the logistical challenges involved in moving to Redmond, I&amp;#8217;m not regretting it one bit.&amp;nbsp;Slowly but surely things&amp;nbsp;are coming together &amp;#8211; our house closed in Toronto today, and we&amp;#8217;re putting together an offer for our new house in Redmond tomorrow. Life is good.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2007 22:48:30 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:b3e8ded7-c2be-4ce8-8057-c561a4ef224c</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2007/02/01/microsoft-is-like-grad-school</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My first week at Microsoft</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. It&amp;#8217;s over. Finally. And now I can reflect back on my first week as a member of the collective. Here&amp;#8217;s some photos of the campus back when there was snow:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s Mt. Rainier towering over Building 42:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/85/364826222_eb41eacb67.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the mountains behind 156 Ave:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/109/364825676_4d1f74a1a6.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The implant didn&amp;#8217;t hurt all that much.&amp;nbsp;My first couple of days at Microsoft involved signing up for various things like benefits, payroll, and parking. It also involved going through New Employe Orientation, where you get to find out some more things about the history, size, and &amp;#8216;diversity&amp;#8217; at the company, as well as things that you can and cannot (well more about the cannot part) do as a Microsoft employee &amp;#8211; essentially your responsibilities as a corporate citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a photo of Building 122:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/114/364826898_ca49955f76.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blog.jonudell.net/2007/01/16/new-employee-orientation"&gt;Jon Udell&lt;/a&gt; was in my orientation class, and he had a great observation about just how confusing the benefits presentation was, and how it can be improved using social networking technology. The idea is to hook up people with similar life circumstances with each other so that they can discuss these things. For example&amp;nbsp;a benefit&amp;nbsp;like the flexible spending account is important to me since Matthew&amp;#8217;s in preschool, but that same benefit would be unimportant to the new college hires that were in my orientation class because of their differing life situation.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;I believe that some of this stuff can be answered using some of the internal mailing lists at Microsoft. As a new hire, I&amp;#8217;m wary about drowning in email, so I&amp;#8217;ve avoided (so far) signing up for those distribution lists. Instead, I&amp;#8217;m relying on the &amp;#8216;hallway advisors&amp;#8217; to help me out. There are a remarkable number of folks that I have met / know that have been out on paternity leave over the past year or so, so there&amp;#8217;s no shortage of people in similar &amp;#8216;family situations&amp;#8217; to me.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I managed to accidentally score a window office as my team is in the middle of an office move. I&amp;#8217;ll enjoy it while it lasts &amp;#8211; I suspect my new office will be next to the boiler room in the basement :)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One example of the sheer size of Microsoft involved getting my alias setup. The seven letters of my name (John Lam) are not unique enough to generate me an alias that would not be ambiguous or just outright silly (and I didn&amp;#8217;t get an ambiguous alias). Thanks to some lobbying on the part of my manager&amp;#8217;s manager, we fought the IT policy &amp;#8230; and won!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I attended my first few team meetings as well, experienced the joys of observing a re-org that I wasn&amp;#8217;t a part of (or frankly could really understand), as well as getting the experience of being the dumbest guy in the room. There&amp;#8217;s an enormous amount of information overload as you walk into a world that, while somewhat familiar from the outside, is very different since everyone here is focused on what the outside world would call a &amp;#8216;future release&amp;#8217;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also spending time figuring out what it means to be a &amp;#8216;Program Manager&amp;#8217;. I suspect that will take the longest amount of time to figure out. But as far as I can tell, it involves an awful lot of meetings :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2007 10:37:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:8e1020ea-1cdb-4c47-9dae-d851e4fe6201</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2007/01/21/my-first-week-at-microsoft</link>
      <category>Life</category>
      <category>Microsoft</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First day in Redmond</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 10 was my first day in Redmond. We (my dog Kobe and I) left home at around 3:30am &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EST&lt;/span&gt; and arrived tired but happy at Sea-Tac airport at 1:30pm &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PST&lt;/span&gt;. The poor dog was locked inside of his kennel the entire time, but he bounced back fast &amp;#8211; he&amp;#8217;s a Black Lab, and he&amp;#8217;s a &lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt; resiliant and good dog.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Once we got to our temporary housing in Sammamish, we promptly got snowed in! This was not what we expected our first night in the Seattle area to be :) We had no food except for the little welcome package that our corporate housing company left for us. Fortunately for us, Dominos was delivering in the snow that night, so Kobe got a lot of human food that night!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The next morning, this is the scene that greeted us outside:&lt;/p&gt; 

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/148/356523966_121a28d7bc.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a photo of our temporary house:&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/140/356524928_4de9bc85fe.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a photo of the house across the street:&lt;/p&gt; 

	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/142/356525859_9591e0c0c9.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I really like this area that we&amp;#8217;re living in (the Timberline region of Sammamish). However, as I discovered later this week, just getting down the hill from here (less than a mile) takes on average 15 minutes in traffic!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Total time into Microsoft averages 40 minutes in the morning. We&amp;#8217;ll have to look for another area to live, as picturesque as this area is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2007 08:52:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:c43b17c2-b450-40e9-b4b7-6052cbfca811</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2007/01/20/first-day-in-redmond</link>
      <category>Life</category>
      <category>Life</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I need a new phone</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Must &amp;#8230; give &amp;#8230; Apple &amp;#8230; more &amp;#8230; money.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;Hope it&amp;#8217;s at Apple stores when I get off the plane in Seattle tomorrow!&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;June? Yikes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 10:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:2e60d43c-0909-4510-b7ff-5d01cf4e9d15</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2007/01/09/i-need-a-new-phone</link>
      <category>Life</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the nice things that you get from putting up with the giant hassle of moving is an opportunity to simplify your life. I just finished packing up all of my &amp;#8216;non-essential&amp;#8217; computer gear. It&amp;#8217;s remarkable how cathartic the experience was. I have a single computer running in the house right now (my MacBook Pro).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I had a couple of servers running downstairs with a ridiculously complex networking setup involving multiple wireless access points, switches and firewalls. I&amp;#8217;m down to a single &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WRT&lt;/span&gt;-54G access point running my wireless network, and I&amp;#8217;m typing this thing on my Mac. I brought my Samsung ML-2150 laser printer up from the basement where it has lived for the past 2.5 years and will plug it into my Mac whenever I need to print (lots of last minute scanning / printing / emailing to do before we go). When I get to Seattle, I doubt that I&amp;#8217;ll miss those servers one bit, as they&amp;#8217;re going into storage while we figure out where we&amp;#8217;re going to live.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll be moving into furnished&amp;nbsp;temporary housing when we get to Seattle. All of the rest of our stuff will go into storage, only to re-emerge when we figure out where we&amp;#8217;re going to live. So we&amp;#8217;ll live for several months with nothing more than what we bring with us on the plane, and a couple of boxes of stuff that we&amp;#8217;re going to ship to ourselves via &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UPS&lt;/span&gt;. It&amp;#8217;s a great opportunity to see how little of our stuff we really need to live &amp;#8211; &lt;strong&gt;especially&lt;/strong&gt; the technology stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 23:09:10 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:b99294a6-6664-4b0a-8d37-4e91cee54409</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2007/01/07/simplicity</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A few quick notes</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost all of my attention has been focused on our upcoming move to Redmond. As I mentioned earlier, it&amp;#8217;s easily the most complicated thing that I&amp;#8217;ve had to organize in my life. We&amp;#8217;re in the end game now, and it&amp;#8217;s&amp;nbsp;feeling like it might actually happen!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m finishing up a consulting project at &lt;a href="http://www.husky.ca"&gt;Husky Injection Molding Systems&lt;/a&gt;. These guys create the machines that make a lot of the plastic goods that we consume &amp;#8211; ranging from pop bottles to laundry baskets. The guys that I work with are professional robot programmers &amp;#8211; and they&amp;#8217;re all over Microsoft&amp;#8217;s recent annoucement of the &lt;a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/robotics/"&gt;Microsoft Robotics Studio&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Industrial robots are optimized for performance, and aren&amp;#8217;t particularly intelligent &amp;#8211; it&amp;#8217;s all about maximizing efficiency in the production of the goods. And while I didn&amp;#8217;t do any robotics programming myself, I&amp;#8217;m amazed by what they can accomplish given the lack of sophistication in the tools that they use to program these things. Some decent tools would go a long ways in improving the lives of robotics programmers &amp;#8211; and perhaps Robotics Studio is a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Jamie Cansdale is organizing a charity auction to raise money for a safe drinking water and irrigation project in Malawi. There&amp;#8217;s lots of useful software that was graciously donated by various companies (and Jamie himself), so make sure you &lt;a href="net-developer-software-charity-auction.aspx"&gt;drop by his blog to take a look.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, I decided to give &lt;a href="http://ideas.live.com/programpage.aspx?versionId=4372c8c2-b76f-4d44-aea1-9835b61d8dc1&amp;nbsp;a"&gt;Windows Live Writer&lt;/a&gt; spin, and am using it to post this blog entry. I was amazed by how seamless the setup experience was for my &lt;a href="http://typosphere.org/"&gt;Typo-powered&lt;/a&gt; blog. I simply entered my blog&amp;#8217;s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt;, and the username and password that I use to administer my blog. It auto-configured everything else. Color me impressed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2006 18:06:50 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:856b8d63-51a1-4dff-a964-8b38efc2a2cc</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/12/18/a-few-quick-notes</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jon Udell joins Microsoft!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many others, I&amp;#8217;ve been a Jon Udell fan for a long time. I&amp;#8217;m really happy that &lt;a href="http://weblog.infoworld.com/udell/2006/12/08.html#a1574"&gt;he decided to join Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; I can&amp;#8217;t think of a better guy to help tell important technical stories to the world.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Now I just have to get to work on converting Jon to Ruby :)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2006 12:07:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:f8ab059e-85b5-405f-8b95-bd1f8896dcd9</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/12/08/jon-udell-joins-microsoft</link>
      <category>Life</category>
      <category>Microsoft</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving on is hard work!</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I barely have enough time to sleep these days as the clock ticks down on our time here in Canada. We&amp;#8217;re living in a state of perpetual cleanliness while we wait for our house to sell. I&amp;#8217;m telling you &amp;#8211; this is no way to live! There are an insane number of details involved with the move &amp;#8211; from figuring out how to get our dog there (there&amp;#8217;s a travel blackout for dogs on Air Canada over the holidays!) to the tax implications of the move itself. Not to mention doing all of those little things like opening a bank account, getting a social security number and a credit card and figuring out how to forward our mail to another country.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;At least the core details: where we&amp;#8217;re going to initially live, how our stuff will get there, and who&amp;#8217;s paying for all that stuff is taken care of by Microsoft. I&amp;#8217;ve got a whole new level of respect for how difficult it must have been for my parents to move themselves (and me) to Canada all those years ago.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Hopefully someday soon I&amp;#8217;ll be able to get back to work on RubyCLR.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I&amp;#8217;ve been listening to a lecture series on my 100 mile daily commute to work. It&amp;#8217;s called the &lt;a href="http://www.longnow.org"&gt;Long Now&lt;/a&gt; and there are many invited lectures on topics that require a long-term outlook (and by long-term, we&amp;#8217;re talking centuries). It&amp;#8217;s somewhat dark at times &amp;#8211; theytackle difficult topics like depopulation and the environment, but there&amp;#8217;s more than a glimmer of hope in all of it. Highly recommended, and a welcome break from just thinking about technology all the time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2006 11:49:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:26283a20-5c75-406e-bd8f-40e2f0cc512c</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/11/18/moving-on-is-hard-work</link>
      <category>Life</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unicode and Ruby</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was quite depressed listening to &lt;a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/"&gt;Tim Bray&lt;/a&gt; talk about Unicode and Ruby at RubyConf. While Tim did a wonderful job at explaining the problems, he didn&amp;#8217;t really provide much in the way of a solution. Which is why I was quite happy when I read Julian Tarkhanov&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=":http://www.fngtps.com/files/2/2006/06/rstm01-unicode_in_rails.pdf"&gt;slide deck&lt;/a&gt; from his Unicode presentation at the &lt;a href="http://www.fngtps.com/2006/05/rails-show-and-tell-meeting"&gt;Rails Show and Tell meeting in Amerstam&lt;/a&gt; where he introduces his &lt;a href="http://julik.textdriven.com/svn/tools/rails_plugins/unicode_hacks/"&gt;Unicode hacks&lt;/a&gt; libraries.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I really like his idea about using an accessor proxy on &lt;code&gt;String&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
name = 'Claus Müller'
puts name.reverse #=&amp;gt; rell??M sualC
name.length #=&amp;gt; 13

puts name.chars.reverse #=&amp;gt; rellüM sualC
name.chars.length #=&amp;gt; 12
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Notice how accessing the same string via the &lt;code&gt;chars&lt;/code&gt; accessor correctly reverses the German string.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2006 06:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:bd4b019f-b218-4ec0-ab9e-ce0e8d0a4daf</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/11/03/unicode-and-ruby</link>
      <category>Ruby</category>
      <category>Unicode</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RubyConf 2006 in pictures</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a &lt;a href="http://www.rubyconf.org"&gt;RubyConf&lt;/a&gt; to remember. I finally went public &lt;a href="http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/10/20/dynamic-languages-microsoft-and-me"&gt;about my move to Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;, and it felt &lt;strong&gt;so&lt;/strong&gt; good to get that off my chest. RubyConf this year was in Denver, and we even got a nice dusting of snow!&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737264/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/99/278737264_b921e140f7.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Snow in Denver!" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I shot quite a few frames, and here are the best of the lot.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Tim Bray, who was quite the character:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737420/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/118/278737420_da11ba1b7c.jpg" width="500" height="330" alt="Tim Bray" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Charles Nutter of JRuby fame:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737385/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/112/278737385_abdeef24e2.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Charles Nutter" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Ryan Davis:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737363/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/88/278737363_40cbb04eb6.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Ryan Davis" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Glenn Vanderburg:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737340/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/113/278737340_883de1cfe6.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Glenn Vanderburg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Laurent Sansonetti from Apple who was the other bridge implementer in the house:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737306/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/79/278737306_3581020fdd.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Laurent Sansonetti" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Nathaniel Talbott, who gave his usual thought-provoking talk:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737295/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/113/278737295_ed472870e2.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Nathaniel Talbott" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Ani Babaian, &amp;#8220;the Microsoft gal&amp;#8221; who took a lot of good-natured ribbing during the conference:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737207/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/109/278737207_b9ab0b6983.jpg" width="500" height="333" alt="Ani Babaian" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a couple of pictures of Matz, who was his usual gracious self:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737129/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/112/278737129_325e5bb349.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Matz" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737153/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/120/278737153_fe7541f610.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Matz" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Masayoshi Takahashi, the famous inventor of the famous Takahashi presentation method on the history of Ruby:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737107/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/114/278737107_0af2b1031c.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Masayoshi Takahashi" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;And last but not least, Rich Kilmer:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737044/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/90/278737044_608d37ebae.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Rich Kilmer" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;and Chad Fowler, our most excellent hosts:&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/john_lam/278737052/" title="Photo Sharing"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/88/278737052_de7dcb625b.jpg" width="330" height="500" alt="Chad Fowler" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2006 21:11:42 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:94791ceb-b94b-4652-8c94-3ca771be28f0</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/10/24/rubyconf-2006-in-pictures</link>
      <category>Ruby</category>
      <category>RubyConf</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
