<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/stylesheets/rss.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better: An Inconvenient Truth</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>John Lam on software</description>
    <item>
      <title>An Inconvenient Truth</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a way, my life was on a collision course with this movie.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;My formal education is in science (I have a Ph.D in Organic Chemistry). I am a skeptic by nature, and I really hate people who hijack &amp;#8220;science&amp;#8221; to support their positions. Science oftentimes has a hard enough time sorting out the truth without help from the lunatic fringe, yet more often than not it winds up self-correcting (I fondly recall grad students from &lt;a href="http://www.utoronto.ca/jpolanyi/"&gt;Polanyi&lt;/a&gt; lab working to debunk the cold fusion debacle of 1989).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I renewed my love affair with my iPod while taking care of my newborn son in the evenings. I spent quite a few hours in the late evening listening to podcasts to help pass the time as I was walking around the house carrying/rocking/jiggling/shushing my son. While searching for new content, I discovered the &lt;a href="http://itunes.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford iTunes site&lt;/a&gt; and started downloading some really great talks &amp;#8211; one of the best was &lt;a href="http://dunbar.stanford.edu/dunbar_ges.html"&gt;Robert Dunbar&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; Reunion Homecoming lecture &lt;a href="https://deimos.apple.com/WebObjects/Core.woa/Browse/itunes.stanford.edu.1770146.01868937.1868982?i=1561505433"&gt;Is Global Warming Real? Climate Change and Our Energy Future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;That talk summarized in a very approachable way the overwhelming amount of evidence about the relationship between &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CO2&lt;/span&gt; levels and global temperatures. This was the first time that I had heard about polar glacial ice core evidence that provides very accurate climatic data that spans many hundreds of thousands of years.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;So at lunch today, I decided to play hookey and went to see a matinee showing of Al Gore&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href="http://www.climatecrisis.net"&gt;An Inconvenient Truth&lt;/a&gt;. The movie is largely based on his presentation on global warming that he has given over a thousand times on the road. It&amp;#8217;s interspersed with personal commentary by Al Gore that reveals a very human element to his story. And what a story it is. You&amp;#8217;ll laugh, you&amp;#8217;ll cry, but most important of all, you&amp;#8217;ll learn something. And perhaps you&amp;#8217;ll be moved enough to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s the really great part of the story. It&amp;#8217;s not all doom and gloom. There is a positive message that carries through the movie: it&amp;#8217;s not too late &amp;#8211; and you can do something about it. As technologists, we like to think that technology can help solve our problems. That&amp;#8217;s a core theme in this movie: embrace technology that helps us reduce our carbon emissions. And developing that technology is not only good business, but a moral imperative.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;When you&amp;#8217;re done, head on over to &lt;a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2006/05/al-gores-movie/#more-299"&gt;RealClimate.org&lt;/a&gt; and read what real climatologists have to say about it. After reading that, you should read this &lt;a href="http://www.tcsdaily.com/article.aspx?id=052406F"&gt;widely cited article&lt;/a&gt; that presents the opposing viewpoint. But please, make up your own mind.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve made up my mind to do something about it. I hope that this blog will help some of you to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Here&amp;#8217;s a link to &lt;a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/cgi/content/full/306/5702/1686"&gt;the Science paper&lt;/a&gt; that surveyed 928 papers and found no papers that disagreed with the concensus view that the evidence for human modification of the environment is compelling.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update 2:&lt;/strong&gt; From the comments, a link to &lt;a href="http://www.norvig.com/oreskes.html"&gt;Peter Norvig&amp;#8217;s analysis&lt;/a&gt; of the Science survey. Peter Norvig is the Director of Search Quality at Google, and the author of one of the &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1558601910"&gt;finest computer science books ever written&lt;/a&gt;. Remember &amp;#8211; be skeptical and check your facts!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2006 22:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:7bec349eabe043d2875b0d2831e5eb95</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth</link>
      <category>Props</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"An Inconvenient Truth" by Pete</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Futuregeek, if you had actually read Peter Norvig's experiment you would have found that he supports the Oreskes study. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"So overall I would say that Oreskes is correct; that Peiser has not shown a peer-reviewed scientific paper that clearly rejects the consensus. I would also say that Peiser is correct in that he found at least 4 papers that place some doubt on some of the premises of the consensus, but he is widely wrong in claiming 34."&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2006 16:56:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth#comment-578</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"An Inconvenient Truth" by futuregeek</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Too bad that survey has been discredited.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href="http://www.norvig.com/oreskes.html"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jun 2006 11:17:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth#comment-551</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"An Inconvenient Truth" by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Al Gore is a conduit for the message. The research is being done by real scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, I was a big skeptic of this stuff myself. But I took the time to educate myself about the science behind the hype. Now, given my background perhaps I have an easier time reading the primary source literature than you may, but perhaps that's why you should put aside any political feelings you may or may not have about Al Gore and just &lt;em&gt;listen&lt;/em&gt; to his story and make up your own mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He does a great job at telling the story. LIsten to it and hopefully be moved enough to fact check for yourself. But make sure that you look carefully at the sources of the argument - question their credentials - question their motivations. In other words be skeptical. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also be open-minded and willing to change if the evidence is convincing enough for you to believe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 15:47:15 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth#comment-549</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"An Inconvenient Truth" by Edwin King</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I've always been a skeptic about human-caused global warming and other issues (e.g., the mythical "ozone hole").  It's beyond arrogant and short-sighted to presume we have any control over the Earth's climate, or any significant influence in relation to the major factors of the Sun, the Earth's dynamic orbit about the Sun, and the Earth's natural dynamism.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aparently our CO2 emissions on Earth are so great that they are affecting other planets in our Solar system:
&lt;a href="http://www.space.com/scienceastronomy/mars"&gt;http://www.space.com/scienceastronomy/mars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;ice-age&lt;/em&gt;031208.html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe there is some common element the both Earth and Mars share...hmmm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ted Danson warned us 20 years ago that we only had 10 years left to repent of our sins and change our evil ways - why should I be frightened by Algore's warnings now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Edwin King&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 13:52:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth#comment-548</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"An Inconvenient Truth" by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kyle, After looking at your first reference, it's clear that the authors draw no conclusions about CO2 contributions to modern day global warming. They're looking at historical data to explain the Little Ice Age phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I find it amusing that both of these references appear in sites that have obvious political undertones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Readers can draw their own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 13:31:57 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth#comment-547</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"An Inconvenient Truth" by Kyle</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Too bad that survey has been discredited.  If Mr. Gore didn't cherry pick his sources and references, he might be more believable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.sepp.org/weekwas/2006/June"&gt;http://www.sepp.org/weekwas/2006/June&lt;/a&gt;%2017.htm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.humaneventsonline.com/article.php?id=15666"&gt;http://www.humaneventsonline.com/article.php?id=15666&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2006 11:55:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth#comment-546</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"An Inconvenient Truth" by Dave Lee</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi John,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just saw An Inconvenient Truth last night too.  Although I didn't cry, I did laugh some and learned even more, drawing me in and keeping me engaged the whole way through.  I have, for many years now, been trying to do little things to reduce my impact on the environment, but after seeing this film I want to take the dive and do bigger things too.  As Al Gore talked about overcoming obstacles that stop people understanding the problem, I similarly hope to remove the obstacles that stop me from doing more, particularly cost and inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2006 13:29:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/06/21/an-inconvenient-truth#comment-544</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
