<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better comments on Embed movies in PowerPoint</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Less is better comments</description>
    <item>
      <title>"Embed movies in PowerPoint": comment by zenspider</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the plug... I was on MacOSX and I used Ambrosia's SnapZ Pro X which, while commercial, is really really good and was worth the money to have a smooth presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that it takes me about 30 minutes to get a good, smooth, roughly error-free 1 minute movie. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 15:56:52 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2005/11/30/embed-movies-in-powerpoint#comment-58</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2005/11/30/embed-movies-in-powerpoint#comment-58</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Embed movies in PowerPoint" by jlam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was something &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; special about &lt;a href="http://blog.zenspider.com/"&gt;Ryan Davis&amp;#8217;&lt;/a&gt; excellent ZenHacks talk at RubyConf 2005. It took me a while to figure out what was going on, but it initially looked to me like he was typing code into a command shell embedded in the middle of his Keynote slide deck. As it turned out, he was playing QuickTime movies from within his slide deck, which let him give the &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; of a live coding session, but with better commentary since he didn&amp;#8217;t have to think, talk and type at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I decided to try the same approach for my talk tonight. However, I quickly ran into a large number of technical blocking issues. Here&amp;#8217;s a set of notes to help anyone else that&amp;#8217;s trying to use this technique.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;a href="http://www.techsmith.com/"&gt;Camtasia&lt;/a&gt; rocks. I have a full license for &lt;a href="http://www.macromedia.com/software/robodemo/"&gt;Captivate&lt;/a&gt; but I think I&amp;#8217;m going to pony up the cash for Camtasia as well. The main reason for the switch is the ability to create &lt;span class="caps"&gt;WMV&lt;/span&gt; files directly from Camtasia.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;2) Your screen cast video will look really crappy if it is scaled. The main problem with PowerPoint is that it &lt;strong&gt;insists&lt;/strong&gt; on scaling your video to whatever your output device resolutiion is. One way to get around this is to force the slide show resolution to a fixed resolution (I used 1024&amp;#215;768):&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="images/screen_resolution.png" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Next, you must force the size of your video clip to be a fixed size (7.8125&amp;#8221; works for an 800&amp;#215;600 movie using the default PowerPoint slide sizes).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;3). Setup your video to play automatically. This makes for a much more seamless experience when you land on a slide with a video. I had a really hard time making things work the way I wanted with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SWF&lt;/span&gt; files generated by Captivate, which was a major reason why I&amp;#8217;m considering ponying up the $$$ to buy Camtasia (it&amp;#8217;s not cheap either, but a good deal cheaper than Captivate).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2005 10:49:00 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/11/30/embed-movies-in-powerpoint"&gt;Embed movies in PowerPoint&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
      <link>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/11/30/embed-movies-in-powerpoint"&gt;Embed movies in PowerPoint&lt;/a&gt;</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
