<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better comments on Dull cubicles or dull people?</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Less is better comments</description>
    <item>
      <title>"Dull cubicles or dull people?": comment by John Lam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roland, What about my comment about university research labs? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My office in Lash Miller Chemical Laboratories was about as institutional as you could get. We're talking harsh fluorescent lighting, an incredibly noisy ventilation system, a steel desk that I rescued from the loading dock, and a 20 year old swivel chair covered in nasty gray vinyl. Yet there was a Nobel Prize awarded to one of our professors in that very same building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm not saying that the environment is not important. What I am saying is that the people are &lt;em&gt;far&lt;/em&gt; more important than the environment. So go ahead and create a better working environment once you've solved the people problem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2006 21:39:34 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people#comment-194</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people#comment-194</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Dull cubicles or dull people?": comment by Roland Kaufmann</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kathy's point was that the introduction of a cubicle environment typically stems from a desire for control, predictability and uniformity, and those factors inhibit creativity and leads to intellectual loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's a myth that good people should be able to perform well regardless of the environment. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2006 15:02:41 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people#comment-184</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people#comment-184</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Dull cubicles or dull people?": comment by J</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to say that I agree with this post.  I work in a cubicle setting right now, but I happen to work with people who are interesting, innovative and frequently give me ideas on how to better do my job.  I'm actually glad that we don't have office doors;  I can turn around, ask a question and have several people give me good answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minus side is that cubicles can get kind of kind of noisy, but that's how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2006 19:32:09 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people#comment-182</guid>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people#comment-182</link>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Dull cubicles or dull people?" by jlam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kathy Sierra posted about &lt;a href="http://headrush.typepad.com/creating_passionate_users/2006/02/brain_death_by_.html#comments"&gt;how cubicles can cause brain damage&lt;/a&gt;. Folks, we&amp;#8217;re mixing up cause and effect.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Nobody likes cubicles. That&amp;#8217;s fine. But simply changing your organization to have beautiful offices with doors that look out over panoramic vistas will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; let you create wonderful products &lt;em&gt;if you keep the same people&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s the people in your organization that make it dull and lifeless. Let&amp;#8217;s face it, the typical graduate student office is about as institutional and ugly as any cube farm, yet remarkable work gets done every day there. Why? It&amp;#8217;s the people.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Look around you. Would you rather have a door to keep the bozos out, or would you rather get rid of the bozos?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2006 10:35:00 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>&lt;a href="/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people"&gt;Dull cubicles or dull people?&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
      <link>&lt;a href="/articles/2006/03/06/dull-cubicles-or-dull-people"&gt;Dull cubicles or dull people?&lt;/a&gt;</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
