<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better comments on TorCamp</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>Less is better comments</description>
    <item>
      <title>"TorCamp" by jlam</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/23649168@N00/67605248/"&gt;&lt;img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/67605248_fc147dbc3a.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;This was &lt;a href="http://barcamp.org/index.cgi?TorCamp"&gt;TorCamp&lt;/a&gt; weekend in Toronto. And what a weekend it was. For the longest time, it felt quite isolating to be a geek living in Toronto (at least relative to places like Seattle or San Francisco). Sure, there&amp;#8217;s a vibrant .NET developer community in Toronto, but most of that community is focused on &amp;#8220;corporate&amp;#8221; apps, and far less on innovative uses of the technology (aka startups).&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.objectsharp.com"&gt;ObjectSharp&lt;/a&gt; was proud to be a sponsor of the initial run of the conference. I met a lot of really interesting folks at the event that I&amp;#8217;m sure I&amp;#8217;ll be having a lot more interesting follow-up conversations with in the near future. A &lt;strong&gt;big&lt;/strong&gt; thanks goes out to &lt;a href="http://davidcrow.ca/"&gt;David Crow&lt;/a&gt; for making this event happen.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/tags/torcamp/"&gt;flickr group&lt;/a&gt; for some images from the conference. I love the space that &lt;a href="http://www.teehanlax.com/"&gt;teehan+lax&lt;/a&gt; provided for hosting the conference.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;The best thing about this conference was the cross-fertilization of ideas that can happen when you get a bunch of folks from different walks of life having informed conversations and debates. &lt;a href="http://www.braithwaite-lee.com/weblog/2005/11/torcamp.html"&gt;Reg Braithwaite&lt;/a&gt; gave a nice talk about the importance of context in applications ranging from search to advertising to project management(!). &lt;a href="http://blog.davidjanes.com/"&gt;David Janes&lt;/a&gt; gave a very cool demo about metadata, microcontent, blogging, and greasemonkey. I met Albert Lai, whose company, &lt;a href="http://www.bubbleshare.com/about/"&gt;BubbleShare&lt;/a&gt; is actually using Ruby and .NET to build their innovative photo sharing service. Lots of other interesting hallway conversations too numerous to recount here.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;I spent some time talking to a small group of folks about bridging Ruby and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CLR &lt;/span&gt;(this wasn&amp;#8217;t really the right crowd to be giving a talk like this to). It started out small, but eventually turned into a 1:1 conversation between myself and &lt;a href="http://shaver.off.net/diary/"&gt;Mike Shaver&lt;/a&gt; of Mozilla about the difficulties of avoiding memory leaks in a process that is running multiple GC-based allocators based on his experience with Mono + Firefox. It&amp;#8217;s definitely something that I need to spend some more time thinking about.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2005 09:57:00 Eastern Standard Time</pubDate>
      <guid>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/11/28/torcamp"&gt;TorCamp&lt;/a&gt;</guid>
      <link>&lt;a href="/articles/2005/11/28/torcamp"&gt;TorCamp&lt;/a&gt;</link>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
