<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="/stylesheets/rss.css"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:trackback="http://madskills.com/public/xml/rss/module/trackback/">
  <channel>
    <title>Less is better: Notation matters</title>
    <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2005/10/28/notation-matters</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description>John Lam on software</description>
    <item>
      <title>Notation matters</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.swiss.ai.mit.edu/~gjs/gjs.html"&gt;Gerald Sussman&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; talk at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;OOPSLA&lt;/span&gt; was tied to one of the themes of this year&amp;#8217;s conference: poetry, the arts, and their relationship to software. He talked about code that is prose, and code that is poetry. He showed us some examples of prose that he wrote: some C code that controlled the servos of a large radio telescope array in Chile. He also showed us some code that is poetry: the two-page implementation of &lt;code&gt;eval&lt;/code&gt; in Lisp.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;He also talked about how writing programs can help improve the way you think. One example came from a first-year graduate level course in &lt;a href="http://www-swiss.ai.mit.edu/~gjs/6946/index.html"&gt;Classical Mechanics at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. In this course, he gets his students to write Scheme code to describe certain equations. The students found that they understood the equations far better when asked to reformulate them using a computer language instead of mathematical notation. There was also the added side effect that they could now perform computations using their equations.&lt;/p&gt;


	&lt;p&gt;Gerald Sussman comes across as a geeky version of &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deion_Sanders"&gt;Deion Sanders&lt;/a&gt;. Deion Sanders was great and he wanted to remind you of it when he spoke. Similarly, Sussman is great and he reminds you of that fact when he speaks as well. Some people find this kind of grand standing offensive. Others, like myself, find nothing wrong with this &amp;#8211; if you can talk the talk &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; walk the walk then that&amp;#8217;s fine by me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2005 07:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">urn:uuid:11276f08d057d68ac5dbd908b728d231</guid>
      <author>jlam@iunknown.com (John Lam)</author>
      <link>http://www.iunknown.com/articles/2005/10/28/notation-matters</link>
      <category>Props</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
